### RESUME FOR THE POST OF SCIENCE TEACHER/BIOLOGY TEACHER

#### **MANOJ SHARMA**



**Objective:** I aim to be a part of one of the best-known schools in terms of academics, culture values and discipline. A school with modern outlook and methods of teaching which makes teaching learning process a wonderful and memorable experience for the child along with due emphasis on the age old traditional values of Education.

## **Professional Qualification**

- **❖ Bachelor of Education (B.Ed.)** with 70.62% From DBRA University Agra (Year 2004 to 2005)
- ❖ Passed CTET Paper II with 76% marks

## **Academic Qualification**

- **❖ Master of Science (M.Sc.)** in Zoology with 67% From MJPR University Bareilly (Year 2002 to 2004)
- **❖ Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.)** Zoology Botany and Chemistry with 64.14% From MJPR University Bareilly (Year 1999 to 2002)
- ❖ 12<sup>th</sup> from CBSE Board with 77.8% (Year 1998) (In Biology 90% and in Chemistry 93%)

# **Teaching Experience**

Working as a teacher since March 2007 and in 15 years of teaching I spent 8 years in Boarding Schools and International Schools in India and abroad.

**Presently** I am working as a teacher in Kendriya Vidyalaya (Under Ministry of Education, Govt. of India). (Since April 2015)

## **Previous Teaching Experience**

# March 2006 to November 2006

- ➤ Worked on ad hoc basis in Sunway Senior Secondary School Rampur as P.G.T. (Bio) against leave vacancy.
- Apart from teaching XI and XII worked as **coordinator for National Children science congress -2006** and guided the students to make project on Aquatic Biodiversity.
- ➤ Project was selected at Zonal and Regional level and cleared for state level.
- **March 2007- June 2009 →**
- As <u>Science Teacher</u> in <u>Templeton Academy International</u> which is a residential school situated in **Nainital**.
- ➤ I have taught class IX to XII biology and class X chemistry.
- July 2009 March 2010. In Rama International School, Purwakarta (Indonesia). As T.G.T Science.
- ➤ March 2010 to March 2012- In Sherwood College, Nainital. As P.G.T Biology and E.V.S. Sherwood College is 150 years old institution and renowned boarding school of India.
- > As House tutor of Robin Hood House at Sherwood College, Nainital.
- ➤ April 2012 to November 2013 in CL Gupta world school, Moradabad as Biology teacher.
- **2013 to 2015** Indus International School, Hyderabad (India) which is an IB and IGCSE School. Taught Biology to middle school and Grade 11.

## RESPONSIBILITIES INCLUDED

- ➤ Planning entire syllabus from class V to class XII, and timely Completion of the Syllabus.
- ➤ Entire planning for Science Department Programs and Activities and Annual Science Exhibition along with preparation of Annual Budget for the Science Department.
- ➤ Complete responsibility and looking after a Senior House comprising of 30 students.
- > Conducting various House Activities, participation in different inter house competitions and maintenance of House Discipline.

### **PERSONAL PROFILE:**

Father's name: Sri V.K. Sharma

**Date of Birth**: 04<sup>th</sup> May 1981

Spouse detail

Name- Parul Sharma

**Educational qualification- B.Sc.(Zoology, Botany & Chemistry)** 

First Division and B.Ed. First division.

Nationality: Indian

No. of Dependent-02 (Age-Son 9 years and 3 years old daughter.

Strength: Situation analyzing/handling, a team worker, good

communication skill, patience and good sense of humor

\_\_\_\_\_

October, 2022

(MANOJ SHARMA)